Well, this is distressing. Musician who
perished in 2021 resurrected as a clump
of brain matter now composing new music.
Yes, a group of researchers and artists
used a musician's donated blood in order
to create a brain organoid. So, a tiny
human brain that you can literally grow
in a jar if you want to and are now
forcing it to compose new music. This
actually happened. Just in case you
weren't familiar, the tiny human brains
can be hooked up to a computer and made
to do various tasks. These particular
enslaved brain organoids were made
posthuminously from a composer, Alvin
Lucier. More or less, it is a push
towards immortality to keep creating as
an artist after your eventual death. I
don't know if we're going to see more of
this, but I suspect we will. These are
the brains in question. They were grown
from the artist's blood. You can
actually use a lot of cells to turn them
into stem cells and into whatever
organoid you want. They hooked them up
to a computer and turned them into an
art exhibit. Yes, they're connected to
these speakers and they compose music.
The researchers are hoping that they'll
see them learning and improving the
composition. And if you really want to
see them, yes, that is on the table. I
have a lot of questions, but first, yes,
you can use these little guys for
computation. In fact, there's a couple
companies that have platforms that you
can rent them out for to do your
computation. 16 organoids to a chip. And
if you want to go see them, you can
watch them think in real time.
Evidently, there was an agreement. The
artist's health had declined in 2021,
and he came to the organization
Revification and wanted to start this
project. He donated his blood. It
actually worked. Although I suspect it's
kind of similar to how plants, if you
hook them up to computer systems, you
can monitor their cellular processes and
make music from that. Although these
little brain organoids also get input
back so they can understand what they're
doing. And if there's any concept of
pattern, brain organoids tend to learn.
They haven't put out a whole lot of
information, so I don't know if it's
like other brain organoid systems where
they're trained on dopamine and ordered
and disordered signals. Yes, brain
organoids are technically sentient
because they're capable of having an
experience and responding to it. And
we're not just talking about how like a
toaster will have the experience of
being turned on and then have an action.
We're talking actual experiences of pain
and joy. If you want to call the
induction of dopamine joy, I would. I
really enjoy dopamine. It's a kind of
immortality that to me sounds kind of
like eternal torment. But hey, whatever
you like, I guess. If you do have
interest in the project, you can just go
ahead and search revification. And I
haven't seen any links to the audio
itself, but as soon as I can find that,
I'll give it to you. This raises a lot
of philosophical questions like is the
experience of being a brain organoid
technically does that belong to the
donor? Because a lot of brain organoids
are made from donated tissue. Can
somebody withdraw consent
posthuminously? If so, if the brain
organoids start talking back and say,
"Hey, end me." Do they have the right to
do so? But hey, perfect timing. We did
just get a new season of Black Mirror.
And if any producers are listening, I
would very much like to one day have my
videos used in an intro.